(浪漫博士 3 季)
(DR. ROMANTIC SEASON 3)
这部电视剧中的角色、地点、组织和事件都是虚构的作品
THE CHARACTERS, PLACES, ORGANIZATIONS, AND EVENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE WORKS OF FICTION
一般来说，把它记得很重要。
Generally speaking, it's important to make it down well.
但是这个叫做骄傲的该死的东西
But this darn thing called pride
让男人表现得小气。
makes a man act petty.
往前看，明白了吗？
Look far ahead, got it?
-还有...-如果你反正要倒下，
- Also… - If you're going down anyway,
你做起来不妨看起来很酷。... 放松一点！
you might as well look cool doing it. …loosen up a little!
戴上护目镜！
Put your goggles on!
但是贪婪和傲慢让你很努力。
But greed and arrogance make you try so hard.
-只有在你变成失事之后...-明白了吗？
- Only after you become a wreck… - Got it?
... 你最终能放手吗。
…will you finally be able to let it go.
这风...
This wind…
别跳。不！不要！
Don't jump. No! Don't!
我告诉你，别跳！
Don't jump, I tell you!
男人没办法吗
Is there no way for a man
看起来很优雅
to look graceful
跌倒时？
while falling?
你这话是什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
我加入你们只有一个条件。
There is only one condition for me to join you.
你将把卜勇珠从突潭医院创伤中心带走。
You will remove Bu Yongju from Doldam Hospital Trauma Center.
我们不能就你的工资或其他条件达成协议吗？
Can't we reach an agreement with your salary or any other condition?
我不是要做个交易，朴主任。
I'm not asking to make a deal, Director Park.
教授，没有金大师我们就无法管理创伤中心。
Professor, we can't run the Trauma Center without Master Kim.
这是不可思议的。
It's unimaginable.
那我们就忘记我们曾经讨论过这个问题了。
Then let's forget we ever discussed this.
查金曼教授
PROFESSOR CHA JINMAN
是我。
It's me.
你想什么时候开始？
When do you want to start?
你想让我什么时候开始？
When would you like me to start?
一周后怎么样？
How about in one week?
届时我会和金大师谈谈。
I'll talk to Master Kim by then.
当然，你将不得不面对其他医生的抵制。
Of course, you will have to deal with resistance from the other doctors.
我已经准备好处理这么多问题了。
I'm prepared to deal with that much.
在你开始工作之前，请让我知道其他细节。
And let me know about other details before you start work.
好吧。
Okay.
是的。到时见。
Yes. I'll see you then.
他说他会做的。
He says he'll do it.
干得好，朴主任。
Good work, Director Park.
-金大师。-是吗？
- Master Kim. - Yes?
我可以问你为什么吗？
May I ask you why?
你为什么做出这样的决定？
Why did you make such a decision?
你确定我们需要他
You determined that we need him
并想把他带到这里。
and wanted to bring him here.
尽管如此，我不想让创伤中心没有你。
Still, I didn't want the Trauma Center without you there.
创伤中心...
The Trauma Center…
一直是你长期以来的梦想。
had been a longtime dream of yours.
把它拿走就是作弊。
Taking that away would be cheating.
朴导演
Director Park.
你知道怎么把大象放进冰箱吗？
Do you know how to put an elephant into a fridge?
答案很简单。
The answer is simple.
把门打开
Open the door.
把大象放进去。然后，关上门。
Put the elephant inside. Then, close the door.
金大师
Master Kim.
但仅仅因为某件事很简单
But just because something is simple
并不意味着任何人都能做到。
doesn't mean anyone can do it.
简单的解决方案并不容易。
A simple solution doesn't make it easy.
你和我刚刚抓住了门把手。
You and I have only just grabbed the doorknob.
查金曼教授！给我一个我儿子的死的答案！
PROFESSOR CHA JINMAN! GIVE ME AN ANSWER FOR MY SON'S DEATH!
（第 3 卷）把大象放进冰箱，第 2 部分
(VOLUME 3) PUTTING AN ELEPHANT IN A FRIDGE, PART 2
这是多尔达姆医院的急诊室。
This is the Doldam Hospital ER.
是的，明白了。
Yes, got it.
张博士，急诊病人在三分钟后就到了。
Dr. Jang, an emergency patient is arriving in three minutes.
哦，好吧。你能帮他包扎一下吗？
Oh, okay. Can you bandage him up, please?
是的，医生。
Yes, Doctor.
哦，你得看看八号床上的撕裂伤口。
Oh, and you need to look at the laceration wound in bed eight.
撕裂伤口？好吧。
Laceration wound? Okay.
张博士，二号床的病人的X光片出来了。
Dr. Jang, the X-ray is out for the patient in bed two.
好吧。
Okay.
哦，我们该怎么处理胃痛的病人？
Oh, what should we do about the patient with the stomachache?
我会做的。
I'll do it.
张博士！八号床上的裂伤口。
Dr. Jang! The laceration wound in bed eight.
-他们已经等了一段时间了。-好吧。
- They've been waiting for a while. - Okay.
医生，血太多了。
Doctor, there's so much blood.
医生，请看这里。
Doctor, please take a look here.
-医生。-我们先来过这里。
- Doctor. - We were here first.
-但这很紧急。-医生。
- But this is urgent. - Doctor.
-等一下。-请帮帮我们。
- Just a moment. - Please help us.
-医生。-我们先来过这里。
- Doctor. - We were here first.
-医生？-医生！
- Doctor? - Doctor!
-对不起。-医生。
- Excuse me. - Doctor.
Jung Insu 博士和 Yoon Areum 还没来吗？
Are Dr. Jung Insu and Yoon Areum not here yet?
荣格博士去见了导演。
Dr. Jung went to a meeting with the director.
而且 Yoon 博士还没来上班。
And Dr. Yoon hasn't come to work yet.
说真的...
Seriously…
我们有病人！
We have a patient!
发生了车祸。
There was a car crash.
腹部有穿透性伤口。BP 是 80/40。心率 120。
A penetrating wound in the abdomen. BP is 80/40. Heart rate 120.
他的血压太低了。我们该怎么办，张博士？
His BP is too low. What should we do, Dr. Jang?
张博士！那胃痛的病人呢？
Dr. Jang! What about the stomachache patient?
张博士！八号床上的裂伤口！
Dr. Jang! The laceration wound in bed eight!
-张博士！-张博士！
- Dr. Jang! - Dr. Jang!
张博士！八号床！
Dr. Jang! Bed eight!
等等... 等一下。
Wait… just a minute.
-八号床！-你在干什么？
- Bed eight! - What are you doing?
-请快来！-很紧急！
- Please come quickly! - It's urgent!
-张博士！-张博士！
- Dr. Jang! - Dr. Jang!
在这里！
Over here!
你现在在干什么？
What are you doing right now?
抓紧吧，朋克！
Get a grip, punk!
我们祝你身体健康
WE WISH YOU GOOD HEALTH
他刚站起来睡着了，对吧？
He just fell asleep standing up, right?
我想他甚至做了一个梦。
I think he even had a dream.
你一定很累，张博士。
You must be very tired, Dr. Jang.
是的...
Yes…
我没事。
I'm okay.
这是个急诊病人！
It's an emergency patient!
这是个26岁的男性。他是国家跳台滑雪队的一员。
It's a 26-year-old male. He's on the national ski jump team.
他在训练中着陆时受伤。
He was injured while making a landing during training.
他的生命体征是 126/82 和 68。
His vitals are 126/82 and 68.
他似乎没有任何外伤，
He doesn't seem to have any external injuries,
但他正遭受极度痛苦。
but he's suffering from extreme pain.
-让我们让他坐混合动力车或。-好吧。
- Let's get him in the hybrid OR. - Okay.
请在这里等着。
Please wait here.
你不来吗？
Aren't you coming?
那郑仁秀博士和尹阿雷姆博士呢？
What about Dr. Jung Insu and Dr. Yoon Areum?
荣格博士正在和导演会面。
Dr. Jung is in a meeting with the director.
而且 Yoon 博士还没来上班。
And Dr. Yoon hasn't come to work yet.
张博士
Dr. Jang.
张博士，快点。
Dr. Jang, hurry.
-哦，你在这里。-是的，你好。
- Oh, you're here. - Yes, hello.
把它放进去。不，不在那里。就是这样。
Put that inside. No, not there. That's it.
等等！这是新的。一定不要碰它。
Wait! That's new. Make sure not to bump it.
-是的，就是这样。-你在干什么？
- Yes, that's it. - What are you doing?
哦，徐博士。你刚来上班吗？
Oh, Dr. Seo. Are you just coming to work?
今天将有一位新的 CT 外科研究员加入我们。
A new CT surgical fellow will be joining us today.
我一直在为他们重新安排。
I've been rearranging for them.
Cha Eunjae 要搬到这个房间吗？
Is Cha Eunjae moving to this room?
没错。从现在起普通外科医生将待在一个房间里
That's right. From now on, general surgeons will be in one room,
而且 CT 外科医生会去另一个地方。
and CT surgeons will be in another.
你将拥有自己的专长。
You will be with your own specialty.
但是，为什么有三张办公桌？
But, why are there three desks?
我不确定。朴明国导演让我再准备一份。
I'm not sure. Director Park Minguk asked me to prepare another.
无论如何，我简直不敢相信我能目睹这个景象。
Anyway, I can't believe I get to witness this sight.
看来只是昨天我们只用金师傅来管理医院。
It seems only yesterday we ran the hospital with just Master Kim.
老实说，当姜东柱博士和尹瑞贞博士加入我们的时候，
Honestly, when Dr. Kang Dongju and Dr. Yoon Seojeong joined us,
我从来没有想过金大师的梦想会成真。
I never imagined that Master Kim's dream would come true.
但是有一个房间里挤满了普通外科医生
But one room is overflowing with general surgeons,
另一个房间里挤满了心胸外科医生。
and another room is full of cardiothoracic surgeons.
最重要的是，创伤中心站得很高。
On top of that, the Trauma Center is standing tall.
我深受感动。
I am so deeply moved.
嘿，一个男人在说话。
Hey, a man is talking.
天哪，他怎么会这么缺乏社交能力？
Gosh, how could he be so lacking in social skills?
我的天哪！对不起，放轻松点。
My goodness! Sorry, go easy on that.
嘿，你在这里。
Hey, you're here.
-你整晚都在工作吗？-当然。
- Did you work all night? - Of course.
我正在待命。我当然工作了一整夜。
I was on call. Of course I worked all night.
我眨眼就睡不着觉。
I couldn't sleep a wink.
你刚才不是在睡觉吗？
Weren't you sleeping just now?
睡觉？谁？
Sleeping? Who?
我没睡。
I wasn't sleeping.
我给你带了些番茄汁。
I brought you some tomato juice.
在混合之前我把它们漂白了。
I blanched them before blending it.
味道应该还可以。
It should taste okay.
你自己做的？
You made it yourself?
-你还把它们漂白了？-是的。
- You even blanched them? - Yes.
我甚至自己把它们烫了。
I even blanched them myself.
嘿，这是什么？
Hey, what is this?
只要吃几个西红柿你就会很感动。
You're quite moving with just a few tomatoes.
当你在玩的时候，也为我打开盖子。拜托？
While you're at it, open the lid for me too. Please?
请问漂亮吗？
Pretty please?
对不起，我还半睡着了。
Sorry, I'm still half asleep.
我的舌头还没完全清醒。
My tongue isn't completely awake yet.
嗯！
Mmm!
这味道不错。太新鲜了。
This tastes good. It's so fresh.
请忘记你刚才听到的内容。你能做到吗？
Please forget what you just heard. Can you do that?
不，我不能。
No, I can't.
这是我的短暂错误，因为我累了。
It was a momentary error on my part because I was tired.
请忘记这件事，好吗？
Please forget about it, okay?
我不想。
I don't want to.
“拜托了。”
"Pretty please."
你又去了。
There you go again.
这个会持续一段时间。什么？“请问漂亮吗？”
This one will last a while. What? "Pretty please?"
停下来，徐宇镇。
Stop it, Seo Woojin.
-“请问漂亮吗？”-嘿。
- "Pretty please?" - Hey.
-漂亮...-嘘。
- Pretty... - Hush.
-可能有人能听见。-好吧，我停下来。
- Someone might hear. - Okay, I'll stop.
-但是 “请问漂亮吗？”好吧，我停下来。-说真的，我说停下来。
- But "pretty please?" Okay, I'll stop. - Seriously, I said stop.
李善农博士这是普通外科的徐宇镇博士。
Dr. Lee Seonung. This is Dr. Seo Woojin in general surgery.
你好。我们上次在船上见面。
Hello. We met on the boat last time.
哦，你一定是新的 CT 外科研究员。
Oh, you must be the new CT surgery fellow.
我是李善宁。
I'm Lee Seonung.
从今天起，我将在多尔达姆医院报到。
As of today, I'm reporting to duty at Doldam Hospital.
金大师雇了我。
Master Kim hired me.
很高兴见到你。我希望我们相处得很好。
It's good to see you. I hope we get along.
拜托了。
Pretty please.
什么？
What?
这是急诊室打来的电话。
It's a call from the ER.
待会儿见，车恩才博士。
See you later, Dr. Cha Eunjae.
祝你有美好的一天。
Have a good day.
他刚才说了什么？
What did he just say?
哦，别介意他。
Oh, don't mind him.
有时候他就是这样。他甚至不好笑，但他尝试了。
He's just like that sometimes. He's not even funny, but he tries.
但是他一点都不好笑，对吧？
But he's not funny at all, right?
天哪，说真的。
Gosh, seriously.
你喜欢番茄汁吗？
Do you like tomato juice?
是的。
Yes.
我们有什么？
What do we have?
他是国家跳台滑雪队的一员。他在着陆时受伤。
He's on the national ski jump team. He was injured while landing.
裴文正医生正在检查他的膝盖韧带。
Dr. Bae Munjeong is looking at his knee ligaments.
但他一直说自己有胃痛。
But he keeps saying he has stomach pain.
-那CT呢？-那个 CT...
- What about the CT? - The CT…
CT 显示前腹部的一部分壁增强。
The CT shows wall enhancement in a part of the front abdomen.
我认为我们需要进行手术观察。
I think we need to do a surgical observation.
-就在这里？-是的。
- Right here? - Yes.
但是在后面，通气看起来不错，而且尺寸很小。
But in the back, the aeration looks good and the size is small.
我认为增强只是肠道肿胀所致。
I think the enhancement is just from the swollen bowels.
没错，但是...
That's true, but…
-腹泻怎么样？-没有。
- What about diarrhea? - There is none.
-他的实验室怎么样？-他的 WBC 是 9,000。
- What about his labs? - His WBC is 9,000.
只有他的 CRP 略有升高。
Only his CRP is slightly elevated.
身体状况？
Physical condition?
RLQ 里有点温柔。
There's some tenderness in the RLQ.
而且没有反弹吗？
And there's no rebound?
它并不突出。
It's not prominent.
要么在那里，要么没有。
It's either there or not.
你说的不突出是什么意思？
What do you mean by not prominent?
病人一直说很痛。
The patient keeps saying it hurts.
-病人在哪里？-在混合动力手术室里
- Where is the patient? - In the hybrid OR.
膝盖韧带没有问题。
There's nothing wrong with the knee ligaments.
对，我说了同样的话，
Right, I said the same thing,
但是病人一直说很痛。
but the patient keeps saying that it hurts.
对不起。
Excuse me.
三年前他接受了前交叉韧带手术。
He had surgery on his ACL three years ago.
哦，但是现在看来还不错。
Oh, but it seems fine now.
我的胃好痛。
My stomach hurts so much.
哦，我的胃。它要死我了。
Oh, my stomach. It's killing me.
让我来看看。
Let me take a look.
嘿，徐博士。你在这里。
Hey, Dr. Seo. You're here.
病人一直抱怨胃痛。
The patient keeps complaining about stomach pain.
但是 CT 扫描中没有任何特别之处。
But there isn't anything in particular in the CT scan.
先生，对不起。
Sir, excuse me for a minute.
抬起你的膝盖。
Bring your knee up.
-我按这里会痛吗？-是的。
- Does it hurt if I press here? - Yes.
那这边呢？
What about this side?
右边还受伤吗？
Does the right side still hurt?
是的，确实如此。
Yes, it does.
让我看看你的衣服底下。
Let me look under your clothes.
如果我像这样点击它会怎样？
What if I tap on it like this?
那也很痛。
That hurts too.
你能用力咳嗽吗？
Can you cough with some force?
你感觉到肚子里有铃声吗？
Do you feel a ringing in your stomach?
是的，我能感觉到。
Yes, I feel it.
让我们尝试不同的位置并进行比较。
Let's try a different position and compare.
抬起你的腿。收紧肌肉。
Lift your legs. Tighten your muscles.
抬起头，看看你的膝盖。
Lift your head and look at your knees.
哪一个更痛？早点还是现在？
Which one hurts more? Earlier or now?
这更痛。
This hurts more.
好吧。你现在可以放松了。
Okay. You can relax now.
张东华.
Jang Donghwa.
是吗？
Yes?
你查过卡内特的牌子了吗？
Did you check for Carnett's sign?
我做到了...
I did…
那你为什么建议做手术观察？
Then why did you suggest a surgical observation?
根本没有肌肉防护。
There's no muscle guarding at all.
对不起。这是什么？有什么不对吗？
Excuse me. What is it? Is something wrong?
没什么大不了的。这是一种常见的疾病
It's nothing big. It's a common illness
称为假装。
called faking.
这是什么？
What is this?
你是故意着陆时摔倒的吗？
Did you fall while landing on purpose?
不，我没有。我真的很受伤。
No, I didn't. I really am hurting.
你为什么不相信我？
Why won't you believe me?
整形外科医生和我都同意。
The orthopedic surgeon and I agree.
考试成绩没有问题。
There is nothing wrong with the exam results.
真是一堆嘎嘎声！
What a bunch of quacks!
如果考试成绩还好，一切都好吗？
Is it all fine if the exam results are fine?
我告诉你我很痛苦！
I'm telling you I'm in pain!
你这个可怜的傻瓜！
You pathetic fool!
比赛还有几天的时间。这是什么？
The competition is days away. What is this?
在这个不敬虔的时刻，你把我们的时间浪费在任何事情上！
You wasted our time fussing over nothing, at this ungodly hour!
我真的很痛苦！
I really was in pain!
算了吧，朋克！为什么，我应该把你撕成碎片。
Forget it, punk! Why, I ought to rip you apart.
先生，你不能在这里这么大声说话...
Sir, you can't speak so loudly here...
你认为赢得一枚金牌是一项巨大的成就吗？
Do you think winning one gold medal is a huge accomplishment?
你呢？不要自欺欺人。
Do you? Don't flatter yourself.
明白了吗？
Got it?
奖牌只是你生命中的一个小圆点。
A medal is just a tiny dot in your life.
你所做的只是在地图上打了一个点。
All you did was put a dot on the map.
你不是大人物。
You're no big shot.
你傲慢自大，甚至不会练习。
You're stiff with arrogance and won't even practice.
现在，你假装受伤了？
And now, you fake an injury?
你...
You…
你知道如果你因傲慢而变得过于僵硬会发生什么吗？
Do you know what happens if you get too stiff with arrogance?
即使是最轻微的错误也可能导致巨大的伤害。
Even the slightest error can lead to a huge injury.
明白了吗？
Got that?
一个人的生活也是一样的。
A person's life is the same way.
朋克。
Punk.
天哪，对不起。
Gosh, I'm sorry.
你在干什么？快起来！
What are you doing? Get up already!
天哪，那个教练太吓人了。
Gosh, that coach is scary.
他一定已经伪造过好几次了。
He must've faked it several times already.
放开他是对的吗？他说他很痛苦。
Is it right to let him go? He says he's in pain.
不过，我们无能为力。
Still, there's nothing we can do.
我也是这么想的。我敢肯定他们有团队医生。
That's what I think too. I'm sure they have team doctors.
让我们尽我们所能，荣格博士。
Let's just do what we can, Dr. Jung.
好吧，如果操作系统和GS是这么说的。
Okay, if that's what OS and GS say.
我现在要让他出院。
I'll discharge him for now.
对不起。
Excuse me.
关于赵成允先生...
About Mr. Cho Sungyoon…
我们不能给他静脉注射然后让他休息几个小时吗？
Couldn't we give him an IV and let him rest for a few hours?
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
压力也是一种疾病。
Stress is a type of illness too.
休息几天他就能好起来。
He could get better with a few days of rest.
GS 外科医生从什么时候开始控制患者的压力水平？
Since when did GS surgeons start to manage patients' stress levels?
对不起？
Pardon?
对，医生可以同情病人。
Right, a doctor can feel sympathetic for a patient.
但仅此而已。
But that's all.
你叫我做我该做的事。
You told me to do what I had to do.
我的意思是你应该在工作中尽力而为。
I meant you should do your best at your job.
你刚才做的就是太过分了。
What you just did is go overboard.
不要混淆这两个。
Don't confuse those two.
说真的。
Seriously.
信息
INFORMATION
一定是缺乏技巧，对吧？
It must be a lack of finesse, right?
-徐博士，我的意思是。-嗯。
- Dr. Seo, I mean. - Mm.
我想他说的话是为了教张博士
I think he says what he says to teach Dr. Jang,
但是张博士似乎被他的话弄伤了。
but Dr. Jang seems to be hurt by his words.
我感觉就像在你早年的时候在看着你。
I feel like I'm watching you in your early days.
天哪。
Gosh.
杨浩俊不是负责居民的吗？
Wasn't Yang Hojun in charge of the residents?
是的，他本应如此。
Yes, he was supposed to be.
我敢肯定他把它传给了徐博士。
I'm sure he passed it on to Dr. Seo.
无论如何，他是世界上最好的
Anyway, he's the world's best
太无耻了，没有责任感。
at being shameless and having no sense of responsibility.
所以...
So…
你不能清理这两者之间的交通吗？
can't you clear up some traffic between those two?
天哪，别烦他们。
Gosh, leave them alone.
如果成年人喜欢这些事情
If grown-ups butt in for these things,
这只会使事情变得更加复杂。
it will only make things more complicated.
他们需要在头上碰头然后紧紧抓住头部。
They need to butt heads and bond over it.
他们就是这样长大的。
That's how they'll grow up.
张东华博士！
Dr. Jang Donghwa!
对金仁国先生来说太棒了
Suction for Mr. Kim Inguk.
在接下来的一个小时里留意这个病人。
Keep an eye on this patient for the next hour.
他是一名患有肠梗阻的糖尿病患者。
He's a diabetic with an intestinal obstruction.
你应该怎么排便？
How should you do a bowel rest?
他不应该口服任何东西然后给他静脉注射。
He should take nothing by mouth and give him an IV.
那是他没有糖尿病的时候。
That's when he isn't diabetic.
一位糖尿病患者
A diabetic patient
可能会进入低血糖。
could go into hypoglycemia.
所以你应该给他 TPN，而不仅仅是液体。
So you should give him TPN, not just fluids.
哦，对。
Oh, right.
如果我发现你又在医院玩游戏
If I catch you playing games in the hospital again,
你将加班两个小时。
you'll work two hours of overtime.
如果你愿意，可以试试看。
Try it if you want to.
张东华
JANG DONGHWA
张医生，你查过明天的手术时间表了吗？
Dr. Jang, have you checked tomorrow's surgery schedule?
我现在在做。
I'm on it now.
说真的。
Seriously.
昨天腹部受伤患者的报告在哪里？
Where is the report on yesterday's abdomen injury patient?
我现在就做。
I'll do it now.
别忘了在今天下午之前整理病例报告。
Don't forget to organize the case report by this afternoon.
是的，先生。
Yes, sir.
你累了吗？
Are you tired?
不，先生。
No, sir.
是的，有点。
Yes, a bit.
这意味着你做得很好。
That means you're doing well.
开始吧。
Here you go.
是的，先生。
Yes, sir.
哦，你在这里。
Oh, there you are.
你做过手术吗？
Did you have surgery?
我有一些练习要做。
I had some practice to do.
我现在完成了。
I'm done now.
很难，不是吗？
It's hard, isn't it?
好吧，没关系。
Well, it's fine.
放轻松。
Take it easy.
简单。
Easy.
我打赌他不明白。
I'm betting that he didn't understand.
你这么认为吗？
Do you think so?
即使对于一个头脑冷静的男人来说
Even for a cool-headed man,
对自己保持客观不是一件容易的事，金大师。
being objective about himself is not an easy thing, Master Kim.
顺便说一句，你说你想告诉我一件事。
By the way, you said you wanted to tell me something.
这是什么？
What is it?
什么？
What?
创伤中心的新负责人？
A new head of the Trauma Center?
谁？
Who?
好吧，
Well,
我也不确定这些传闻是否属实。
I'm not sure if the rumors are true either.
我听说查金曼博士将出任创伤中心主任。
I hear Dr. Cha Jinman will be coming as head of the Trauma Center.
查金满博士，你的意思是...
By Dr. Cha Jinman, do you mean…
车恩才的爸爸？
Cha Eunjae's dad?
是的。
Yes.
希望，爱，服务
HOPE, LOVE, SERVICE
行政办公室
ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE
哇！
Wow!
多么漂亮。这太完美了！
How nice. This is perfect!
现在我有了新大三学生，好事正在发生。
Great things are happening now that I have a new junior.
现在，CT外科医生正在接管多尔达姆医院。
Now, CT surgeons are taking over Doldam Hospital.
让我们扫一扫吧，好吗？
Let's sweep the board, okay?
我缺乏实践经验。我还有很多东西要学。
I'm lacking in practical experience. I have a lot to learn.
别担心。别紧张。
Don't worry. Don't be nervous.
如果你有任何问题，可以随时问我。
If you have any questions, ask me anytime.
如果您需要任何帮助，请寻求帮助。
And if you need any help, ask for it.
你很快就会明白，但是 Doldam 的每个人都很好。
You'll catch on soon enough, but everyone here at Doldam is nice.
好吧...
Well…
当心 GS 中的杨浩俊博士。他没那么好。
Just watch out for Dr. Yang Hojun in GS. He's not that great.
顺便问一下，为什么有三张办公桌？
By the way, why are there three desks?
哦...
Oh…
我不确定。
I'm not sure.
没办法。
No way.
凭借他的技能和名字价值，这并非不可能。
With his skills and his name value, it's not out of the question.
事实上，我们从中受益匪浅，吴女士。
In fact, we're gaining a lot from this, Ms. Oh.
是朴局长又在做吗？
Is it Director Park's doing again?
确实如此，对吧？他强迫你这样做。
It is, right? He pressured you into this.
天哪。不，不是。
Gosh. No, it isn't.
这次他说什么是为了走自己的路？
What did he say this time to get his own way?
他有没有利用开场日期来对付你？还是紧急直升机？
Did he use the opening date against you? Or the emergency helicopter?
他用了什么样的借口
What kind of excuse did he use
偷走创伤中心负责人的位置？
to steal the position of head of the Trauma Center?
我不是从他那里偷的，吴女士。
I didn't steal it from him, Ms. Oh.
我从外面听见你的声音。
I heard your voice from outside.
我不是故意的，但我无意中听见了你的谈话。
I didn't mean to, but I overheard your conversation.
我很高兴你已经听见我说话了。
I'm glad you already heard me.
亲自告诉我。
Tell me in person.
你在隐瞒什么样的阴谋
What kind of plot are you hiding
这个荒谬的人事任命的背后？
behind this ridiculous personnel appointment?
没有情节。
There is no plot.
我很生气，吴女士。
I'm upset, Ms. Oh.
在过去的三年中，我一直以忠诚和真诚的态度工作。
I've been working with loyalty and sincerity over the past three years.
把它称为忠诚和真诚的决定难道不是太荒谬了吗？
Isn't this too absurd of a decision to call it loyalty and sincerity?
你怎么能在万物的这种立场下做到这一点？
How could you do that with that position of all things?
你是如何发展这种随机而毫无意义的创造力的？
How do you develop such random and senseless creativity?
我告诉过你这是我的主意。
I told you it was my idea.
我就是这个意思！这是金大师的主意...
That's what I mean! It was Master Kim's idea…
-什么？-我说过我们应该这么做。
- What? - I said we should do it.
-但是...-MINGUK：看。
- But… - MINGUK: Look.
稍后让我们澄清误会。
Let's clear up the misunderstanding later.
我们现在去我的办公室吧。
Let's go up to my office for now.
查金满教授刚到。
Professor Cha Jinman just arrived.
我们开始做吧。
Let's do that.
稍后。
Later.
-我们待会儿再谈，吴女士。-但是...
- Let's talk later, Ms. Oh. - But…
-我们走吧。-好吧。
- Let's go. - Okay.
但是为什么？
But why?
为什么在地球上？
Why on earth?
那我就让你说话。
Then I'll leave you to talk.
我很感激你来到这里，查教授。
I'm so grateful to have you here, Professor Cha.
欢迎。
Welcome.
这里。
Here.
我已经想出了一份加入创伤中心的医生名单。
I've come up with a list of doctors to join the Trauma Center.
啊，是的。
Ah, yes.
他们中的一些人给了我积极的回应。
A few of them have given me positive responses.
多尔达姆医院创伤中心推荐医生名单
DOLDAM HOSPITAL TRAUMA CENTER RECOMMENDED DOCTOR LIST
多尔达姆的外科医生不在这里。
The Doldam surgeons aren't on here.
我还没能确认他们的技能。
I haven't been able to confirm their skills yet.
你不必担心。
You don't have to worry about that.
多尔达姆外科医生的专长是治疗创伤患者。
The Doldam surgeons' specialty is treating trauma patients.
金大师把注意力集中在那个领域
Master Kim has focused on that area
并训练他们成为一支优秀的团队。
and trained them to be a good team.
朴导演
Director Park.
我对人的评判标准
My standards of judging people
和卜勇珠的完全不同。
is quite different from Bu Yongju's.
我的教学风格也应该有很大的不同。
My style of teaching should differ greatly as well.
没办法。
No way.
你的意思不是因为我你会把外科医生排除在Doldam之外，对吧？
You don't mean you will exclude surgeons from Doldam because of me, right?
我的意思是我们不能给多尔达姆外科医生任何特殊待遇。
I mean we can't give Doldam surgeons any special treatment.
该中心依靠政府资金运作。
This center runs on government funding.
规则必须公平。
The rules must be fair.
此外，技能在治疗创伤方面可能很重要，
Besides, skill may be important in treating trauma,
但团队合作也是如此。
but so is teamwork.
你说过你会根据技能做出公平的判断。
You said you'd judge fairly based on skill.
但在我看来，你会有非常个人化的标准。
But it sounds to me that you will have very personal standards.
老实说，很明显，如果他们向你学习，他们会是什么样子。
To be honest, it's obvious how they'd be if they learned from you.
他们会鲁莽，粗鲁无理，
They will be reckless, insolent,
或者出于傲慢而乐于使用手术刀。
or happy to wield a scalpel out of arrogance.
像这样的人。
People like that.
你喜欢这样的孩子。
You like kids like that.
我偏爱那些为患者尽其所能的医生。
I do favor doctors who do what they must for patients.
而且，如果他们的手牌很好，那就更好了。
And if they have good hands, even better.
一只好手并不总是能成为好医生。
A good hand doesn't always make a good doctor.
没错。
Exactly.
就像考试成绩好也不能造就好医生一样。
Just like how good test scores don't make good doctors either.
好吧...
Well…
我认为我们现在无法就人事问题做出决定。
I don't think we can decide on personnel matters right now.
你这么自信吗？
Are you so confident?
如果我没有信心
If I weren't confident,
我会安排这个会议吗？
would I have set up this meeting?
我敢肯定你知道我的标准
I'm sure you know that my standards
非常挑剔和保守。
are very picky and conservative.
我确实记得你心胸狭窄、固执的天性使我感到沮丧。
I do remember that you frustrated me with your narrow-minded and stubborn nature.
好吧，距离创伤中心开业还有一段时间。
Well, we still have some time until the Trauma Center opens.
所以，在适当的时候...
So, in due time…
那我们开始做吧。
Let's do it, then.
让我们看看多尔达姆的外科医生有多出色。
Let's see how good Doldam's surgeons are.
如果你自己动手会更好。
It would be better if you operate yourself.
我想看看你这么久以来有多出色。
I want to see how good you are since it's been so long.
我想知道这些年来你的技能提高了多少。
I wonder how much your skills have improved over the years.
-你没喝这个，对吧？-金大师
- You're not drinking this, are you? - Master Kim.
我想知道
I wonder
如果你生锈了。
if you've gotten rusty at all.
让我们在适当的时候讨论人事问题。
Let's discuss personnel matters in due time.
我给你看你要使用的房间，查教授。
I'll show you the room that you will be using, Professor Cha.
房间？
Room?
我会给你指路。
I'll show you the way.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
查教授？
Professor Cha?
你真的会没事吗？
Will you really be okay?
别问。
Don't ask.
我对这个决定后悔了大约三秒钟。
I was just regretting this decision for about three seconds.
他还没签合同。
He hasn't signed the contract yet.
现在告诉我你是否改变主意还为时不晚。
It's not too late to tell me if you've changed your mind.
我们甚至无法在开门之前结束事情。
We can't end things before we even open the door.
那么最终，你真的会进入这扇狭窄的门吗？
So ultimately, you really will enter this narrow door?
如果你拿起一把剑
If you pick up a sword,
你至少能做的就是解开它的护套。
the least you can do is unsheathe it.
好吧。
Okay.
记住。那是我给你的最后一次机会。
Remember. That was the last chance I gave you.
当我第一次在创伤中心见到你的时候
When I first saw you in the Trauma Center,
你就像复仇者联盟。
you were like the Avengers.
-说真的。-复仇者联盟？别恭维我。
- Seriously. - The Avengers? Don't flatter me.
无论如何，我很荣幸能和你一起工作。
Anyway, I'm honored to work with you.
荣幸？
Honored?
李博士，你用了这么甜言蜜语。你很荣幸。
Dr. Lee, you use such sweet words. You're honored.
我真的觉得你给人留下了深刻的印象。
I really think you're impressive.
完全可以理解。我知道我们的外科医生给人留下了深刻的印象。
Totally understandable. I know we surgeons are pretty impressive.
嗯！
Mmm!
李博士，你是我们的幸运符。
Dr. Lee, you're our lucky charm.
这是你自己混的吗？天哪。
Did you blend this yourself? Gosh.
我没成功，但很不错，对吧？
I didn't make it, but it's good, right?
嗯！
Mmm!
这是什么，徐博士？
What is it, Dr. Seo?
这是 CS 房间。在你进来之前敲门。
This is the CS room. Knock before you come in.
李博士
Dr. Lee.
你去过急诊室吗？
Have you been to the ER yet?
你想环顾四周向急诊室的人打个招呼吗？
Do you want to look around and say hi to the ER folks?
为什么？你有什么要跟我说的吗，徐博士？
Why? Do you have something to tell me, Dr. Seo?
你不觉得你有话要跟我说吗，查博士？
Don't you think you have something to tell me, Dr. Cha?
稍后。
Later.
我们待会儿再谈。
Let's talk later.
我现在和李博士有关系。
I have something to do with Dr. Lee right now.
李博士，你能给我们一会儿房间吗？
Dr. Lee, could you give us the room for a moment?
我有事要和查博士讨论。
I have something to discuss with Dr. Cha.
是的，当然。
Yes, of course.
不，李博士！
No, Dr. Lee!
-没必要离开。-好吧。
- There's no need to leave. - Okay.
我只需要五分钟，李博士。
I just need five minutes, Dr. Lee.
哦，好吧。
Oh, okay.
李博士，你只需要听另一位 CT 外科医生的话。
Dr. Lee, you only need to listen to a fellow CT surgeon.
李博士
Dr. Lee.
来吧，我敢肯定你听错了。
Come on, I'm sure you misheard something.
所有地方的创伤中心？那个地方是金大师的...
The Trauma Center of all places? That place is Master Kim's...
我从金大师本人那里听到的。
I heard it from Master Kim himself.
我知道。所以，主人... 什么？
I know. So Master… What?
他为什么突然做出这个决定？
Why did he make that decision all of a sudden?
如果朴局长没有向他施压
If Director Park didn't pressure him,
他自己做出了这个决定，
and he made this decision himself,
这更像是个谜。
it's even more of a mystery.
也许，
Perhaps,
可能是因为他的多发性硬化症吗？
could it be because of his multiple sclerosis?
他的症状可能在我们不知情的情况下变得更糟了。
His symptoms might have gotten worse without our knowing.
来吧，没办法。
Come on, there's no way.
他在休息日去钓鱼，
He's been going fishing on his days off,
呼吸充足的新鲜空气和锻炼身体。
getting plenty of fresh air and exercise.
他一直在努力保持健康。
He's been working hard to keep up his health.
对，上个月我们做了一些血液检查和其他检查时，
Right, when we did some bloodwork and a few other tests last month,
他所有的结果都还不错。
all his results were okay.
对，我怀疑是这样，吴女士。
Right, I doubt that's what it is, Ms. Oh.
如果不是这样，我就是根本不明白。
If that's not it, I just don't understand it at all.
你在这里干什么？
What are you doing here?
我需要一个解释，先生。
I need an explanation, sir.
什么？
What?
天哪。
Gosh.
首先，金大师。
First of all, Master Kim.
查金曼是创伤中心主任？
Cha Jinman as head of the Trauma Center?
有吗
Is there
我们不知道的其他原因？
some other reason that we don't know of?
如果不是，我就是不明白。
If not, I just don't get it.
不，吴女士。
No, Ms. Oh.
这个职位应该向任何有能力的人开放，
That position should be open to anyone capable,
即使那不是我。
even if that isn't me.
说你听不懂
Saying that you can't understand that
是一个危险的想法。
is a dangerous thought.
我知道。
I know.
我们都在为创伤中心努力工作。
We've all been working very hard for the Trauma Center.
而且，如果不是你的努力和奉献精神，
And if not for your efforts and dedication,
我们不会走这么远。
we wouldn't have gotten this far.
但是努力和奉献精神
But effort and dedication
应该在你给他们的那一刻就被抛在后面。
should be left behind the moment you've given them.
希望能得到某种形式的付款
Hoping for some kind of payment
或者要求认可你的输入，
or demanding recognition of your input,
事情会瞬间变成一团混乱。
things will turn into a muddy mess in a flash.
但是，
But,
创伤中心的负责人应该是负责的领导者。
the head of the Trauma Center should be the leader who will take charge.
这个职位应该填补
That position should be filled
经过更仔细的考虑。
after more careful and meticulous consideration.
如果你们都继续努力
If all of you keep working hard
在你各自的位置上
in your respective positions,
仅仅因为我们雇了人就不会发生任何激烈的事情
nothing drastic will happen just because we hired someone
从外面看来是创伤中心的新主任
from the outside to be the new head of the Trauma Center.
我的天哪。
My goodness.
我知道。
I know.
这对我们来说也将是一次考验。
This will be a test for us too.
但是，
However,
一旦开业我们就会有更多的创伤病人
we will have more trauma patients once we open,
那我们就需要更多的医生。
then we'll need more doctors.
如果不接受新医生，
Without accepting new doctors,
你认为我们还能坚持多久？
how much longer do you think we can hold out?
所以拜托，
So please,
毫无偏见地接受我的决定。
accept my decision without any bias.
好吧，吴女士？
Okay, Ms. Oh?
土壤。
Doil.
张局长和裴博士也是
Chief Jang and Dr. Bae too.
好吧。
Okay.
郑博士和恩达也是。
Dr. Jung and Euntak too.
你呢，徐宇镇博士？
And you, Dr. Seo Woojin?
发生了什么事？
What's going on?
在创伤中心准备好之前我会和你共用这个办公室。
I'll be sharing this office with you until the Trauma Center is ready.
我在问你为什么来多尔达姆医院。
I'm asking why you came to Doldam Hospital.
朴主任给了我创伤中心主任的职位
Director Park offered me the position of the head of the Trauma Center,
我接受了。
and I accepted.
爸爸！
Dad!
你可以在医院叫我爸爸吗？
Is it okay for you to call me Dad in the hospital?
如果你是创伤中心的负责人，那金大师呢？
If you're the head of the Trauma Center, what about Master Kim?
我的意思是，你为什么辞去大学医院的工作？
I mean, why did you quit your job at the university hospital?
为了什么？
What for?
我从当今社会获得了很多特权。
I've received much privilege from today's society.
什么？
What?
多亏了这一点，我获得了荣誉并成为众人瞩目的焦点。
Thanks to that, I've received honor and been in the limelight.
现在是我还钱的时候了。
It's time for me to pay it back.
对于社会来说，
For society,
我打算从这里开始承担责任并履行职责。
I intend to take on responsibility and perform my duties from here.
-爸爸。-最重要的是，
- Dad. - And most of all,
我也想见你。
I wanted to see you too.
对不起，先生，
I'm sorry, sir,
但这次我不同意你的决定。
but I can't agree with your decision this time.
为什么不呢？你还需要更多的解释吗？
Why not? Do you still need more of an explanation?
不，你说的一切我都明白。
No, I understood everything you said.
我只是...
I just…
我不同意。仅此而已。
can't agree with it. That's all.
我告诉过你了。你没必要那样保持警惕。
I told you. You don't need to keep your guard up like that.
查金满教授是一位才华横溢的外科医生，在该领域拥有丰富的经验。
Professor Cha Jinman is a talented surgeon who has experience in the field.
有了这个机会，
And with this opportunity,
从局外人那里得到客观的评估并不是一个坏主意。
it won't be a bad idea to get an objective evaluation from an outsider.
你是唯一能评价我作为医生的人。
You're the only one who can evaluate me as a doctor.
你也是我唯一想被认可为医生的人。
You're also the only one I want to be recognized by as a doctor.
嘿，宇镇。
Hey, Woojin.
没有你我就不想要创伤中心。
I don't want a trauma center without you.
如果你决定待在这里
If you decide to stay here,
我也会。
I will too.
我们能聊一会吗？
Can we talk for a minute?
所以...
So…
我爸要来多尔达姆医院了
My dad will be coming to Doldam Hospital.
我收到金大师的来信。
I heard from Master Kim.
哦，我明白了。
Oh, I see.
这是什么？
What is it?
嗯？
Hm?
你有话想对我说。告诉我。
You have something you want to say to me. Tell me.
好吧，问题是...
Well, the thing is…
我爸说他还没找到住的地方所以...
My dad says he hasn't found a place to stay yet, so…
对不起，我们该怎么做？
Sorry, what do we do?
那我所有的东西呢？
What about all my stuff?
我们还没把它们拆开，所以它们还在箱子里。
We haven't unpacked them, so they're still in boxes.
如果我说我有室友，他就不会进入你的房间。
If I say that I have a roommate, he won't go into your room.
你能不能待在别的地方等他过几天才找到地方？
Could you please stay somewhere else until he finds a place in a few days?
我调查了一下，但公司住房已经满了。
I looked into it, but company housing is already full.
他说他会睡在旅馆里，
He said he would sleep at an inn,
但他必须一路走进城里。
but he'd have to go all the way into town.
我已经有一年没有见到他了，所以我不放心。
I haven't seen him in a year, so I didn't feel at ease.
好吧，我待在医院。
Okay, I'll stay at the hospital.
你没生气，对吧？
You're not mad, are you?
根本没有。
Not at all.
谢谢。
Thanks.
-恩宰。-是吗？
- Eunjae. - Yes?
他是你爸爸。
He's your dad.
而且我是你的男人。
And I'm your man.
你不必这么难问我，好吗？
It doesn't have to be so hard for you to ask me, okay?
好吧。
Okay.
别被抓住。
Don't get caught.
好吧，我不会。
Okay, I won't.
对不起番茄汁了。
Sorry about the tomato juice.
嘿，那个番茄汁...
Hey, that tomato juice…
好吧。
Okay.
到了该死的医院帕克教授
ARRIVED AT DOLDAMN HOSPITAL PROFESSOR PARK
一般来说，把它记得很重要。
Generally speaking, it's important to make it down well.
但是这个叫做骄傲的该死的东西
But this darn thing called pride
让男人表现得小气。
makes a man act petty.
-他为什么要那样做？-你在哪里？
- Why did he do that? - Where are you?
-他在想什么？-他在哪里？
- What was he thinking? - Where is he?
我们来了！
We're coming!
-快点！-Sungyoon！
- Hurry up! - Sungyoon!
-我觉得很严重。-快点。
- I think it's serious. - Hurry.
嘿，成云。
Hey, Sungyoon.
-你还好吗？-他的腿骨折了！
- Are you okay? - His leg is broken!
这条路。
This way.
-Sungyoon！-教练！
- Sungyoon! - Coach!
教练！
Coach!
-快点！-我们必须帮助他！
- Hurry up! - We have to help him!
-快点！-哦，不。
- Hurry! - Oh, no.
快点！教练！
Hurry! Coach!
-耐心点。-嘿，你打了 911 吗？
- Endure it. - Hey, did you call 911?
别碰他。
Don't touch him.
你好，我在这里。
Hello, I'm here.
呵呵？
Huh?
嘿，荣格博士。我在这里。
Hey, Dr. Jung. I'm here.
嘿，尹阿雷姆博士。
Hey, Dr. Yoon Areum.
那好吧。
All right then.
嗯？
Hm?
无论如何，这是金大师的决定。
Anyway, it was Master Kim's decision.
查博士到底是什么样的人？
What kind of person is Dr. Cha exactly?
好吧，他在心胸外科领域相当出名。
Well, he was pretty well-known in cardiothoracic surgery.
呵呵？
Huh?
尹博士你来得早。你今晚没待命吗？
Dr. Yoon. You're here early. Aren't you on call tonight?
我有一些论文要看。但是，裴博士。
I had some papers to look over. But, Dr. Bae.
医院里的心情怎么样？
What's with the mood in the hospital?
哦。
Oh.
天哪，金大师刚才引爆了一枚巨大的炸弹。
Gosh, Master Kim set off a massive bomb just now.
五...
Five…
我能帮你什么忙吗？
Can I help you with anything?
你在这里。
You're here.
我听说了。
I heard.
显然，金大师今天引爆了一枚核弹。
Apparently, Master Kim set off a nuclear bomb today.
我知道。
I know.
他做到了。
He did.
我们做什么？感觉就像每个人都在精神崩溃。
What do we do? It feels like everyone is having a mental breakdown.
你还好吗，恩塔克？
Are you okay, Euntak?
这对我来说也是一种崩溃。
It was a breakdown for me too.
但听了金大师的解释后
But after hearing Master Kim's explanation,
我明白他为什么要做他所做的事情。
I understood why he did what he did.
这始终是问题所在。
That's always the problem.
每当金大师引爆炸弹时
Whenever Master Kim sets off a bomb,
你会想，“这有意义吗？”
you think, "Does this make any sense?"
但是当你听他说话时，你总能理解他。
But then when you hear him out, you always understand him.
你有没有时差呢？
Are you jet-lagged at all?
我很好。我在两天内就调整好了。
I'm fine. I adjusted within two days.
哦，对。
Oh, right.
这里。
Here.
我在回来的路上在机场买的。
I bought it at the airport on my way back.
我错过了把它交给你的机会。
I missed the chance to give it to you.
因为你的手很珍贵。
Since your hands are precious.
我想念你。
I missed you.
我们只分开了一个星期。
We were only apart for a week.
但是你怎么能
But how could you
一次都没给我发过短信？
not even text me once?
你去偏远地区做义工。
You went to volunteer in a remote area.
“我想念你。”
"I miss you."
“你什么时候回来？”
"When are you coming back?"
“快回来。”
"Come back soon."
我好像在大放异彩。
I'd seem like I was throwing a fit.
这始终是问题所在。
That's always the problem.
你会想，“这有意义吗？”
You think, "Does this make any sense?"
但是当我听见你说话的时候
But when I hear you out,
我一直都能理解你。
I always understand you.
嗯！
Mm!
你说你想念我。
You said you missed me.
我想看看你有多想念我。
I want to check how much you missed me.
嗯！
Mm!
我们在医院，尹博士。
We're in the hospital, Dr. Yoon.
看见了吗？你没那么想我。
See? You didn't miss me that much.
还剩 40 分钟。
There are still 40 minutes left.
什么？
What?
直到你下班。
Until you get off work.
尽管如此，今天下午我们的病人并不多。
Still, we didn't have very many patients this afternoon.
张博士
Dr. Jang.
什么？
What?
我做错什么了吗？
Did I do something wrong?
这是什么？
What is it?
是的，多尔达姆医院急诊室？
Yes, Doldam Hospital ER?
是的。
Yes.
是的，明白了。
Yes, got it.
有人在滑雪时摔倒了。他们将在五分钟后到这里。
Someone fell while skiing. They'll be here in five minutes.
什么？
What?
这让我发疯了。
This is driving me nuts.
我们祝你身体健康
WE WISH YOU GOOD HEALTH
这是什么样的病人？
What kind of patient is it?
又有人在滑雪时摔倒了。
Someone fell while skiing again.
我们被告知这是开放性骨折。
We were told it was an open fracture.
下个月，平昌将有一场世界锦标赛。
Next month, there's going to be a World Championship game in Pyeongchang.
我们可能会继续看训练时受伤的患者。
We'll probably keep seeing patients who get injured while training.
急诊病人！
Emergency patient!
-Sungyoon。-嘿，等一下。
- Sungyoon. - Hey, hang in there.
-Sungyoon！-我们在医院。
- Sungyoon! - We're at the hospital.
真是一堆嘎嘎声！
What a bunch of quacks!
如果考试成绩还好，一切都好吗？
Is it all fine if the exam results are fine?
我告诉你我很痛苦！
I'm telling you I'm in pain!
什么？
What?
转到混合动力车或！现在！
To the hybrid OR! Now!
请。
Please.
这条路。
This way.
-中间的床！-这边！
- The middle bed! - This way!
先生。
Sir.
-小心。-请在外面等着。
- Be careful. - Please wait outside.
徐博士！
Dr. Seo!
-先生！-这是他的腿。
- Sir! - It's his leg.
让我们把他抬起来。一、二。
Let's lift him up. One, two.
小心点。
Be careful.
好吧。
Okay.
等一会儿，爸爸。一秒钟。
Just a second, Dad. One second.
一秒钟...
One second…
等一下，爸爸！
Just a second, Dad!
只需一秒钟。
Just a second.
这是我的衣服。
It's my laundry.
只需一秒钟。
Just a second.
进来吧，爸爸。
Come in, Dad.
既漂亮又舒适。
It's nice and cozy.
你一个人住在这里吗？
Do you live here alone?
不，我有室友。
No, I have a roommate.
我说过你要来，所以我的朋友住在医院。
I mentioned you were coming, so my friend is staying at the hospital.
医院？
The hospital?
你的室友是医生？
Your roommate is a doctor?
什么？
What?
是的，好吧...
Yes, well…
是 Doldam 医院的 Yoon Areum 博士。
It's Dr. Yoon Areum at Doldam Hospital.
她是一名急诊医生。
She's an emergency medicine doctor.
我的房间在这边。你可以把你的东西留在这里。
My room is this way. You can leave your stuff here.
我会做的。
I'll do it.
开始两次静脉注射，然后用 500cc 的温盐水开始补水。
Start two IV lines, and start hydration with 500cc of warm saline.
去找两个应急包 RBC
Get two emergency pack RBCs.
然后准备十个 RBC 和八个 FFP。
And prepare ten RBCs and eight FFPs.
是的，医生。
Yes, Doctor.
徐博士，你找到流血的焦点了吗？
Dr. Seo, have you found the bleeding focus?
是 hemoperitoneum。
It's hemoperitoneum.
张东华，把那边往上开。
Jang Donghwa, open that side up.
一路打开！
Open it up all the way!
这是他的脾脏。
It's his spleen.
荣格博士，英国石油公司已经 80 岁了 40 岁以上。
Dr. Jung, BP is 80 over 40.
-准备 RIS！-是的，医生。
- Prepare the RIS! - Yes, Doctor.
Areum，开始实验吧。
Areum, get the labs started.
好吧，我会准备好的。
Okay, I'll get it ready.
他的脉搏真的很弱。
His pulse is really weak.
他可能也受了血管损伤。
He might have a vessel injury too.
腓骨动脉？
The popliteal artery?
是的，有可能。
Yes, it could be.
有抽水吗？
Was there any pumping?
不，现场没有。
No, there wasn't any at the scene.
严女士，请南博士开一个手术室。
Ms. Eom, ask Dr. Nam to open up an OR.
-然后打电话给 Cha Eunjae 博士。-是的，医生。
- And call Dr. Cha Eunjae. - Yes, Doctor.
让我们在这里暂时放个夹板。
Let's get a temporary splint on here.
-荣格博士，看他服用镇静剂。-好吧。
- Dr. Jung, see him through sedation. - Okay.
Euntak。
Euntak.
我会准备好的。
I'll get it ready.
-我们给他插管吧。-是的，医生。
- Let's get him intubated. - Yes, Doctor.
张东华，你来帮忙。
Jang Donghwa, you assist.
什么？
What?
张东华，别胡说八道！
Jang Donghwa, stop dawdling!
戴上磨砂膏。快点。
Get your scrubs on. Hurry.
对不起。过来了
Excuse me. Coming through.
发生了什么事？
What's going on?
是急诊病人吗？
Is it an emergency patient?
好吧，也许吧？我想是这样。
Well, maybe? I think so.
让我们开始吧。手术刀。
Let's begin. Scalpel.
但是先生，这是急诊室。
But sir, this is the ER.
准备大量的纱布以防出血。
Prepare a lot of gauze for the bleeding.
是的，医生。
Yes, Doctor.
Bovie。
Bovie.
吸气！大胶带！
Suction! Large tape!
理查森。
Richardson.
镊子。
Forceps.
抽吸。
Suction.
我说，吸气！
I said, suction!
别碰那个。你在压碎胰腺。
Don't touch that. You're crushing the pancreas.
哦，好吧。
Oh, okay.
Euntak，和张东华切换。
Euntak, switch with Jang Donghwa.
钳制。
Clamp.
这里还有一个。
Another one here.
请领带。
Tie, please.
切。
Cut.
另一个。
Another.
我们会暂时封住脾动脉
We'll temporarily hold the splenic artery,
把它装上纱布做个 CT 然后带他去手术室
pack it with gauze, get a CT, and get him to the OR.
-切。-切。
- Cut. - Cut.
-给我找个封面。-好吧。
- Get me a cover. - Okay.
我们正在转移病人。
We're moving the patient.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你是来玩的吗？
Are you here to have fun?
你在干什么，只是站在旁观看？
What are you doing, just standing around and watching?
对不起，我太傻眼了。
I'm sorry, I was so dumbstruck.
快点行动起来，然后跑到手术室。
Get your act together fast and run over to the OR.
我们马上就要开始脾切除术了。
We're starting a splenectomy right away.
快点做好准备。
Get ready quickly.
继续前进！
Get a move on!
徐博士
Dr. Seo.
张东华是第三年居民。
Jang Donghwa is a third-year resident.
您至少应该在此过程中解释一些事情。
You should at least explain things along the way.
他必须知道自己在做什么才能继续下去。
He has to know what he's doing to follow along.
现在，病人是第一位的。
Right now, the patient comes first.
没时间留意张东华的心情。
There's no time to look out for Jang Donghwa's mood.
你怎么了？你的行为不像你自己。
What's wrong with you? You're not acting like yourself.
你为什么这么着急？
Why are you in such a rush?
那个病人
That patient
在国家队里。
is on the national team.
那么？
So?
从今天早上起他就是病人
He's the patient from this morning
那是我因为假装他的痛苦而送走的。
that I sent away for faking his pains.
你真的对拉米恩还好吗？
Are you really okay with ramyeon?
我通常在外面吃饭或者点菜。
I usually eat out or order in.
我没意识到我已经没米了。
I didn't realize I was out of rice.
外送食物味道也不错。
Delivery food tastes good too.
没关系。别介意我。
It's fine. Don't mind me.
我不喜欢拉面。
I don't dislike ramyeon.
嗯。
Mm.
是医院吗？
Is it the hospital?
是的。他们认为这是一条腓骨动脉破裂。
Yes. They think it's a ruptured popliteal artery.
开始吧。
Get going.
完成后把碗放在水槽里即可。
Just leave the bowl in the sink when you're done.
-我回来的时候去洗碗。-好吧。
- I'll do the dishes when I get back. - Okay.
手术可能会延迟，所以不要等。
The surgery might run late, so don't wait up.
好吧。
Okay.
这是今天早上剩下的西红柿。喝酒前要摇匀。
IT'S THE TOMATOES LEFT FROM THIS MORNING. SHAKE WELL BEFORE DRINKING.
女士更衣室
WOMEN'S LOCKER ROOM
嘿，李博士。你还在这里吗？
Hey, Dr. Lee. Are you still here?
你要回家吗？
Are you going home?
我回家后回来做紧急手术。
I went home and came back for an emergency surgery.
紧急手术？
An emergency surgery?
我也可以去手术室吗？
May I also go into the OR?
这是什么？
What is it?
你能有多幸运？天哪。
How lucky can you get? Gosh.
这种稀有物到底来自哪里？
Where on earth did this rarity come from?
快点做好准备。
Hurry up and get ready.
今天我来教你一堂课。
I'll teach you a lesson today.
禁区手术室
RESTRICTED AREA OPERATING ROOM
CT 扫描似乎显示损坏
The CT scan seems to show damage
在胫前动脉和后动脉中
in the anterior and posterior tibial artery
在远端区域而不是腓骨动脉。
in the distalis region rather than the popliteal artery.
我们必须做一些探索，
We'll have to do some exploring,
但从我穿夹板时看到的情况来看，
but from what I saw while putting on the splints,
这似乎是腓骨的深层神经。
it seems to be the deep peroneal nerve.
恩宰，那动脉吻合术呢？
Eunjae, what about the artery anastomosis?
周围有很多组织损伤，
There's a lot of tissue damage around it,
所以我正在考虑从另一侧移植GSV。
so I'm considering a GSV graft from the other side.
为了预防隔室综合症，
In order to prevent compartment syndrome,
Munjeong 也在考虑做筋膜切开术。
Munjeong is considering a fasciotomy as well.
你会怎么处理腓骨神经？
What will you do about the peroneal nerve?
纱布。
Gauze.
好吧。Bovie。
Okay. Bovie.
等着这里。
Hold here.
镊子。
Forceps.
Metzenbaum 剪刀。
Metzenbaum scissors.
对不起，先生。
Sorry, sir.
去除脾脏。
Remove the spleen.
请用纱布。
Gauze, please.
缝合。
Suture.
让金大师上线
Get Master Kim on the line.
大师，
Master,
我们将在五分钟内完成缝合。
we'll finish suturing in five.
我们会从 neurorhaphy 开始吗？
Will we start with neurorrhaphy?
你在说什么？动脉是第一位的。
What are you saying? The arteries come first.
他是国家队的一员。
He's on the national team.
如果我们不尽快消除紧张情绪，他可能再也不会跳下去了。
If we don't stitch up the nerves soon, he might never get to jump again.
如果我们不尽快找到他的动脉，他可能会失去整条腿。
If we don't get to his arteries soon, he might lose his whole leg.
大师。
Master.
切。
Cut.
张东华，你做闭合缝合。
Jang Donghwa, you do the closing sutures.
三分钟之内。
Within three minutes.
张博士
Dr. Jang.
把它交给我。
Give it to me.
大师。
Master.
我们不能先做神经疗法吗？
Can't we do the neurorrhaphy first?
徐宇镇.
Seo Woojin.
如此严重的骨折意味着受伤部位的末端被压碎。
A fracture this serious means the end of the injury site is crushed.
即使你在探索之后做了神经外科手术，
Even if you do a neurorrhaphy after exploring,
可行性太低了。我们不能延迟动脉吻合术。
the viability is too low. We can't delay the artery anastomosis.
如果他不能从神经损伤中恢复过来
If he doesn't recover from the nerve injury,
无论如何，他作为运动员的生活已经结束了。
his life as an athlete is over anyway.
不管怎样，对那个人来说都是死刑。
Either way, it's a death sentence for that man.
尽管如此，与其冒险，
Still, rather than taking a risk,
我认为先做动脉手术是正确的，徐博士。
I think it's right to do the arterial surgery first, Dr. Seo.
神经在受伤的那一刻就开始死亡。
Nerves start to die the moment they sustain an injury.
那不是最好尽快把它们缝回去吗？
Then isn't it best to stitch them back up as soon as possible?
金大师以你的速度，这是可能的。
Master Kim. With your speed, it's possible.
大师。
Master.
你为什么犹豫不决？
Why are you hesitating?
嗯？
Hm?
所有手术都必须优先考虑患者的生命。
All surgeries must prioritize the patient's life.
其次是患者的安全。
Next is the patient's safety.
关于功能的决定排在最后。
Decisions on function come last.
这里的每个人都知道。
Everyone in here knows that.
那你为什么要浪费时间？
So why are you wasting time?
你没在想
You're not thinking
像疯子一样先做神经疗法，对吗？
of doing a neurorrhaphy first like a madman, are you?
我们正在考虑哪种方法对这位患者来说是最好的方法。
We're contemplating what would be the best method for this patient.
那你为什么要考虑这个呢？
So why are you contemplating that?
救他的命令已经确定了。
The order to save him is already set.
对那个病人来说
To that patient,
他作为运动员的生活也危在旦夕。
his life as an athlete is also on the line.
如果你错过了手术时机，他将失去运动员的生命
If you miss the timing to operate, he will lose his life as an athlete
还有他的腿。
as well as his leg.
或者，他可能不会输任何一个。
Or, he might not lose either one.
好吧，吴女士。
All right, Ms. Oh.
你能检查一下病人左脚的肤色吗？
Could you check the complexion of the patient's left foot?
看起来不错，金大师。
It's looking good, Master Kim.
宇镇。你还需要多久才能完成关闭？
Woojin. How much longer do you need to finish closing?
张东华博士
Dr. Jang Donghwa.
我受够了。
I'm done.
-切。-切。
- Cut. - Cut.
我们结束关门了，金大师。
We're done closing, Master Kim.
我们先做动脉吗？还是 neurorrhaphy？
Are we doing the arteries first? Or the neurorrhaphy?
先是 Neurorhaphy。
Neurorrhaphy first.
好吧，首先是神经疗法。
Okay, the neurorrhaphy first.
你不应该从患者的角度来看待。
You shouldn't look at the patient's perspective.
你必须看看症状，卜博士。
You must look at the symptoms, Dr. Bu.
这就是为什么我刚才检查了他的症状。
That's why I just checked his symptoms.
你没听见他左脚的肤色又回来了吗？
Didn't you hear the complexion in his left foot is back?
那意味着
That means
两条动脉有一条没有受损。那意味着
one of the two arteries hasn't been damaged. And that means
先紧张情绪不会有太大的风险。
it won't be too much of a risk to stitch up the nerves first.
别这么业余。
Don't be such an amateur.
你生锈了吗？
Are you getting rusty?
天哪，他什么都知道。
Gosh, he knows everything.
他甚至有这个想法。
He even had that in mind.
我们进去吧，查博士。
Let's go in, Dr. Cha.
哦，好吧。
Oh, okay.
车恩才，
Cha Eunjae,
你是说你会去做那个手术吗？
are you saying you will go into that surgery?
什么？
What?
你会参加那种冲动和鲁莽的手术吗？
You will participate in that impulsive and reckless surgery?
这不是鲁莽的。
It's not reckless.
他看见了我们看不见的东西。
He sees what we can't see.
金大师在处理创伤方面有丰富的经验。
Master Kim has a lot of experience dealing with trauma.
是的，没错。
Yes, that's right.
不管是谁，
Whoever it is,
不管他做什么或者他处于什么职位
no matter what he does or what position he is in,
他什么也没想。
he doesn't think about anything else.
他只记住一件事。
He just keeps one thing in mind.
救病人。
Save the patient.
无论如何都要救病人。
Save the patient, no matter what.
那是金大师教给我们的第一堂课。
That was Master Kim's first lesson that he taught us.
你认为这是拯救一个人生命的手术吗？
Do you think that's a surgery to save a person's life?
对于那个病人来说
For that patient,
他作为运动员的生活是他生活的一部分。
his life as an athlete is a part of his life.
你们...
You guys…
和他一样疯狂。
are just as crazy as he is.
有时候，有些关卡你不发疯就无法达到。
Sometimes, there are levels that you can't reach without going crazy.
还有金大师...
And Master Kim…
称之为浪漫。
calls it romance.
浪漫？
Romance?
在一个危及人们生命的领域
In a field where people's lives are at stake,
他在谈论寻找爱情？
he talks about finding romance?
是的。
Yes.
到目前为止，我们就是这样救人的，教授。
That's how we've been saving people up until now, Professor.
车恩宰，你不去吗？
Cha Eunjae, aren't you going?
如果没有，我就去。
If not, I'll go.
爸爸，我们待会儿再谈。
Dad, let's talk later.
宇镇。
Woojin.
浪漫？
Romance?
你说浪漫？
Romance, you say?
嗯。
Mm.
手术刀。
Scalpel.
(浪漫博士 3 季)
(DR. ROMANTIC SEASON 3)
在所有方面...
In all things…
-是呕血。-病人还没死。
- It's hematemesis. - The patient isn't dead yet.
... 有基本原理和原则。
…there are fundamentals and principles.
他刚刚死于心力衰竭。
He just died from heart failure.
不管这位老太太是否犯了纵火罪...
Whether this old lady committed arson or not…
争论谁是好人，谁是坏人。
Debating over who is good and who is bad.
嘿。你不妨去当法官或检察官
Hey. You may as well go be a judge or prosecutor
而不是在这里！
instead of being here!
这是查金满教授今天上午寄来的名单。
This is the list that Professor Cha Jinman sent this morning.
他表现得好像不会带任何人一起去。
He acted like he wouldn't take anyone with him.
那多尔达姆医院的急诊室呢？
What about the emergency room at Doldam Hospital?
希望被证明是徒劳的那一刻，
The moment hope proves futile,
唯一剩下的就是残酷的现实。
the only thing left is the harsh reality.